星际之门亚特兰蒂斯 前情提要
PREVIOUSLY ON STARGATE ATLANTIS
Sheppard少校？！
Sheppard少校，这些都是谁？！
Major Sheppard?!
Major Sheppard who are all these people?!
我叫Teyla Emmagan
是Tughan的女儿
I am Teyla Emmagan Daughter of Tughan
如果幽灵的触角没有到达你们的世界
那你们应该回到那里
If the wraith have never touched
your world you should go back there.
我们也想啊，但是我们办不到
Oh we'd like to but we can't.
我还没见过这种生命体
居然可以像我们一样自然死亡
I don't see a life form like this ever
dieing of natural ageing the way we do.
你侵入我们的捕食域
You trespassed upon our feeding ground.
你不知道你做了一件多么愚蠢的事情
You don't know what you have done.
这里是Sheppard少校的情报与指挥中心
Its Major Sheppard's IDC
他们离开也才几个小时
They've only been gone a few hours.
亚特兰蒂斯，我是Sheppard
我们正加速赶到
Atlantis, this is Sheppard we're coming in hot.
放下防御体系
Lower the shield
升起防御体系
Raise the shield.
Mckay！
McKay!
医疗队到门厅来
Medical team to the gateroom!
感觉有脉搏
I got a pulse
你感觉怎么样？
How you feeling?
我不能说话了 你确实不能说话啊
You can't talk either
你身体里的感觉和运动
神经系统处于超负荷状态
Your body experienced a full overload
to its sensory and motor nervous system?
Ah quwat?
你脸上中了幽灵的击昏器
You took one of those wraith
stunners right in the face?
It's really quite fascinating actually;
幽灵的武器使你的神经元麻痹
那些神经元可使……
the wraith weapon impedes a fire of neurons
that enables the necessary---
什么？
Quwat?
麻痹是暂时的
别担心，Rodney
The paralysis is only temporary.
Don't worry Rodney.
不久你就可以起床走动了
You'll be up and about in no time.
真幸运，这种幽灵武器是设计来 否则他死定了
麻痹人的
Bloody good thing that wraith weapon
is only designed to incapacitate?
or he's be dead
什么？
Quwat?
少校，可以请你过来一下吗？
Major? Could I see you for a second?
Allo? Allloooo?!
他会没事的……
He's going to be fine...
我听说……
我想知道到底都发生了什么……
I've heard...
I want to know what happened out there...
还不是老样子……
The same old thing...
也就是说你们在几次任务里就
Which makes it the fifth time
your teams encountered the wraith
碰到了5次幽灵？
out of... how many missions?
9次
nine...
所以这应该不是巧合
so... probably not a coincidence.
我想这已经非常明显了
这里有间谍
I think it's pretty damn obvious now.
We've got a spy in Atlantis.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第5集 疑云重重
Season 1 : Episode 5
Suspicion
你能不能不要在这挠脚？
Could you please not do that here?
十分抱歉，但我的脚麻得受不了了
My foot is still numb, if you'll excuse me...
看来至少你的口齿还挺灵的嘛
Well at least your mouth still works fine
好了，我们开始吧
Alright let's get started.
不等Teyla了吗？
Shouldn't we wait for Teyla?
Teyla不在与会之列
Teyla wasn't invited.
她是我队里的一员
She's a member of my team
她也是Athosian人
She's also an Athosian sir.
然后呢？
So?
如果我们保持妥协
有许多证据证明我们……
If we've been compromised and
every indication suggests that we have...
几乎可以肯定有人是有嫌疑的
It is almost certain that one of them is responsible
我们在说Teyla……
We're talking about Teyla...
我也不想这样，少校
I don't like it either Major...
好啊，那就把她请来
Good then get her on in here
但我现在必须先考虑这个基地
以及人员的安全
but the safety of this base and its personnel
are my main concern... right now.
原本这是你的责任
As it should be yours.
幽灵在你们的队伍拜访过
的9个星球中的5个出现
The wraith have shown up on the last five
of the nine planets you team has visited
而且根据掌握的情况
其中有两个星球是无人居住的
and given the fact that two
of those world were unpopulated...
所以我们可以极其肯定一定是
有内贼向他们通报了你们的行踪
we can pretty much assume that they have been
alerted to your missions by someone on this base.
如果这个基地里有人和
幽灵保持联络
If someone on this base was
communicating with the wraiths...
那为什么亚特兰蒂斯没有被攻击？
then why hasn't Atlantis been attacked?
说的好
Good point...
也许我们该无限期的停止
星际门的使用
Maybe we should just stop
using the Stargate indefinitely
——不能这样
——为什么？
- We can't do that...
- Why not?
因为我们需要ZPM来给这里提供能量
Because we need ZPMs to power this place.
一切似乎都运转良好
Things seem to be running fine right now...
OK……如果幽灵真的出现……
他们会的……我们要怎样进行防御？
Ok... When the wraith do show up...
And they will... How do we defend ourselves?
更远一点说，这还关系到
我们回地球的事情
Or for that matter how do we get back to earth?
这是飞马星系中唯一能跟地球
连接的星际门
This is the only Stargate in the Pegasus
Galaxy that can even reach earth...
如果真的到了那一步，我们就得
在幽灵占领城市之前使用自毁系统
and if it comes to that we're going to have to use
the self destruct before the Wraith take the city.
底线是：我们能使用星际门
Bottom line: We need to use the gate.
所以我们要尽快找出谁是主谋
Then we've got to find out who's responsible ASAP.
我建议我们先把无关人员
限制在南部区域活动
I suggest we start by confining all non-base
personnel to the south side of the complex.
你是在说笑吗？
Are you kidding?
那是我们至少应该做的事情
如果Sumner上校还在这里的话……
That's the absolute minimum we should do.
If Colonel Sumner was still here...
他不在
He's not.
而我在
I am.
是的，长官
Yes sir.
我们不打算像对待犯人一样
对待我们的战友
We're not going to start treating
anyone like prisoners...
嗯，不错
Well, that's good.
你意味着
That said.
应该采取措施加强
敏感区域的防范
Steps should be taken to safeguard
the more sensitive areas of this facility.
这才是合理的
It's only reasonable.
我建议禁入区先从星际门控制台
I recommend that no go zones
start with Stargate operations,
实验室，能量发生器
以及探险者号开始
the labs, power generation and the Jumper bay.
我想见一下基地上所有的Athosian人
I'd like to meet with every Athosian on this base.
我是说他们来这儿已经3个月了
I mean they've been here three months...
我只知道其中一些人的名字
I only know a handful of them by name,
这里一结束
我就可以安排好会面
I could start setting up interviews
as soon as we're done here...
同时……所有的使用
星际门的活动都暂停，直到有新通知
In the mean time...
all gate travel is suspended. Until further notice.
对不起，女士
你不能上去
Sorry ma'am you can't come up...
我要去见Weir博士
I'm on my way to see Dr Weir.
这里是限制区
That area's of limits.
什么时候开始的？
Since when?
我相信一定是有误会了
I believe there has been
some sort of misunderstanding...
有个会议没通知我……
I... was unaware a meeting had been called...
我们边走边说
Lets take a walk...
怎么了？
What is happening?
亚特兰蒂斯上可能有人泄密
There may be a security leak on Atlantis.
你确定？
Are you certain?
不是十分确定……但很确定
Well Not certain certain... but pretty certain.
也就是说我们必须采取临时
的警备措施
It means we're going to have
to take temporary precautions.
比如说？
Such as?
嗯……比如……停止使用星际门
Well...like uh... suspending gate travel,
加强保安
认识你们的人……更多一些
tightening security...
getting to know your people... better
你们怀疑Athosian人？
You suspect an Athosian?
Weir博士想见他们
就这样，没有针对个人
Dr Weir wants to meet them...
that's all... it's nothing personal.
呃……我是说……
她想亲自见见你们
Well... well I mean it is...
in the sense she wants to meet them all personally
你也十分清楚我们世代
遭受幽灵的侵袭所承受的苦痛
You're aware of the horrors generations
of my people have faced at the hands of the wraith...
就算这样你还怀疑他们的忠诚……
and yet you would still question their loyalty...
喂，Teyla，不能这么说
Come on Teyla... that's not fair...
你们的人在亚特兰蒂斯活动
而许多她都没见过
You've got people running around
Atlantis that's she's never even met.
我知道每一个人
我愿意性命担保他们是清白的
I know each and everyone of them.
I would stake my lives on their innocence
OK……也许你也注意到了
每次我们通过星际门的时候那些坏家伙就来攻击我们
ok... well perhaps you've noticed that every time
we step through the Stargate bad guys try to kill us.
我对此有些感到厌烦了……你呢？
and I'm getting a little tired of it... How bout you?
那也不意味着……
That does not mean-
看……我们所需要的……
只是一点配合，这就够了
look... all we're asking for...
is a little cooperation that's all.
我们会合作的
You shall have it.
Halling
Jintu近况如何？
How's Jintu?
他一直限制在生活区活动，一切都很好
Well enough for a boy confined to his living quarters.
对不起，这是暂时的
但也是必须的预防措施
I'm sorry, it's temporary
but it is a necessary precaution.
我知道
So I've heard.
那么我猜你也知道
我们为什么安排这些会议了
Then I assume you know why
we've arranged these meetings...
跟我们的人不能到别的星球以及
不能去这个城市的别的区域的原因是一样的
For the same reason my people
can no longer go off-world or...
你们不再相信我们了
enter parts of the city. You no longer trust us.
没错，Halling
我们不知道该相信谁
Truth Halling. We don't know who to trust.
关于外星探索的消息显然已经
被泄露给幽灵了
Information regarding some off-world excursions
has obviously found its way to the wraith.
显然？
Obviously?
他们不可能遍布整个星系
而守株待兔
They can't be lying and waiting
in every corner of this galaxy.
他们在跟踪我们的行动
我们现在必须查清楚
They are tracking our movements
and we have to find out how.
我们十分需要你们的配合
Your help with this will be greatly appreciated.
那么究竟……我要怎样才能帮的上忙？
Then by all means... how can I be of assistance?
谢谢
Thank you
自从你来到亚特兰蒂斯以来
你已经参加了3次外星探索了？
Since you've been here on Atlantis...
You've been off-world three times?
是的，我曾经作为向导参与了
Stackhouse军士长的勘测队
Yes I've been acting as a guide on behalf
of Sgt Stackhouse's reconnaissance team...
帮助他们和我们之前的交易伙伴
进行沟通
helping to establish relations between your people
and some of our former trading partners.
Stackhouse报告说在几次出外活动中
他和你失散了
Stackhouse reported he lost track
of you on a couple of these outings...
我是去看望了些老朋友
I did take the time to visit some close friends.
有意思。你出去3次有2次
一天后我们就被幽灵攻击了
Interesting. Two of your three visits predated
wraith attacks by approximately a day
军士
Sergeant.
——你是在暗示什么呢？
——我没有暗示什么
- What are you suggesting?
- I'm not suggesting anything.
你认为我会背叛我自己的人民？
危害我儿子的性命？
You think I would betray my own people?
Jeopardize the life of my son?
没有人在进行指控
No one is making accusations
我不同意。你们已经直接下结论
是有Athosian人泄密了
I disagree. You have already leapt to
the conclusion that an Athosian is responsible.
因为这不可能是我们的人干的
Because it can't possibly be one of our own people...
不
No.
我们只想弄清一些事情
We just need to clarify a few things.
那么听我说……在一次幽灵的对
我的家园的攻击中，我失去了最好的朋友
Then allow me... I lost my closest friend in the wraith
attack that forced us from our home world.
Sellena，在我之前被你们问话的那个女人
失去了她的双亲
Sellena, the woman you spoke to before me,
lost both her parents.
事实上，你很难找到一个
In fact, you'd be hard pressed to find an Athosian
没有因为幽灵的攻击而造成创伤的Athosian人
that has not experienced loss at the hands of the wraith.
这就是你们正在指控的人！
These are the people you accuse.
我们没有指控任何人
We're not accusing anyone.
并且我来这儿是来接受采访的
而不是审问
And I came here expecting an interview...
Not an interrogation.
我认为这不是很……
I mean I don't think it's too much to ask...
什么？
What is it?
没什么……没什么……
nothing... nothing...
就是不能忍受日复一日的
吃同样的饭菜
Just can't bear the same meal
day after day after day...
振作些
我正在诊断
Well buck up a little...
I'm trying to run a diagnostic.
对不起
Sorry.
我是说……我们被困在另一个星系
只有有限的资源
I mean... we are stranded with limited
resources in another galaxy.
拜托，最近的一家bob-big boys在3百万光年远
我们需要……
Come on the nearest bob-big boys is three hundred
million light-years away... we have to make do...
如果你想连续两天吃掉我最喜欢的东西
那你就吃吧
If that means you have to eat my favorite
food two days in a row... so be it.
你喜欢吃那些军队供给的食物吗？
You enjoy military rations?
我知道……这很奇怪
医院的东西我也喜欢
I know... it's weird... Hospital food too.
我不喜欢飞机上的食物的唯一原因是
我不能要两份的，我是一个……
The only reason I don't like aero plane food
is you can't get seconds and I'm an absolute...
Hello...
怎么了？
What is it?
这是一个我从未见过的
命令子路线
Well it's a command sub routine
I've never seen before...
什么功能？
What is it's function?
不知道，因为我从未见过这玩意儿
I don't know... because I've never seen it before.
OK，我去对照一下控制室里的
和这有关的远古数据库
Ok, I'm going to cross reference this with
the ancients data base up in the control room...
我要去找那个……
I'm just going to grab the a...
你碰了什么？
What you touch?
——没有，没有……
——不，你刚刚……
——不，没有，我没有
- nothing nothing...
- No you were just...
- No no no I didn't.
我不知道顶棚还可以这样
I had no idea the roof could do that.
我也是
Neither did I...
门厅和休闲区对我们关闭了
The gateroom and surrounding
sections have been closed to us.
而且我们再也不能在没有护卫的情况下
进医疗室了
And we may no longer have access
to the medical facility without escort.
我们被时刻监视着
行动被限制
We're under constant surveillance...
our movements restricted.
我们这样要忍多久？
How long must we put up with this?
已经太久了
It has already been to long...
我想我应该被邀请到你们的讨论中来
I would have been expected
to be included in this discussion...
因为我们期望你能对我们的防守措施
表明态度
As we would have expected you
to take a stand in our defense...
他们已经采取措施来保护
基地的所有人
They have taken action
to defend everyone on this base.
这也包括你们每一个人
幽灵的内贼的存在对我们每一个来说都是威胁
That includes each and every one of you.
The presence of a wraith collaborator threatens us all.
那么你支持Weir博士对我们
的禁行令了？
Then you support Dr weir's decision to confine us?
Halling……我们是他们的客人
Halling... we are their guests.
现在我们更像是囚犯……
但和囚犯不同的是……
We've become more like their prisoners...
but unlike prisoners...
我们可以选择离开
we can choose to leave.
你们要去哪里？
Where would you go?
你为什么没说“我们要去哪里”？
Do you not mean to say "Where would we go?"
在其他星球上也有朋友
他们一定很欢迎我们的
We have friends on other worlds
who would gladly take us in...
住多久？好的贸易伙伴并不一定
是好客的主人
For how long? Good trading partners
do not necessarily make good hosts...
这里有很多星球
There are many worlds among these stars.
幽灵已经唤醒了
没有哪个星球是安全的
The wraith have awakened... no world is safe.
留下也不安全
nor is it safe to remain...
他们会一直这样下去
直到找到替罪羊为止
They will continue to do this until
they find someone to blame.
你打心里知道我们中间
不会有叛徒的
You know in your heart that none of
our people could be responsible for this...
当然
Of course.
那我们就没什么好怕的
Then we have nothing to fear.
你真的这么相信Weir博士？
You trust Dr Weir that much?
是的
I do.
——胜过相信自己的人民？
——不！
- More that you would trust your own people?
- No!
我知道她的责任感
I understand her responsibility
Hallin
我们一次次的碰到幽灵出击
那么经常而迅速
We have met with the wraith offworld
so often and so quickly...
一定有个原因，而不是巧合
there must be a reason beyond coincidence...
让他们查清楚吧
Give them a chance to find it.
他们的有些措施我也不赞成
I do not a approve of some of their measures...
但是我知道最终他们
会证明我们是清白的
but I do know in the end they
will help to prove our innocence.
亚特兰蒂斯不单是个避难所
它承载着希望
Atlantis is far more than shelter. It is hope.
不单对我们的人民
而且对每一个跟幽灵抗争的人们
Not only for our people but for everyone
who would stand against the wraith.
我们不应该放弃希望
We must not abandon that hope.
他们也许会定居在这儿，Teyla
但他们不是祖先
They may reside here Teyla
but they are not the ancestors.
不管你有多么愿意他们是
No matter how much you wish them to be.
长官
Sir.
Ford...
我听说他们在探险者号发射台那儿
打开了天棚
Heard they got a sun roof open on the jumper bay...
没错
Yep...
我也听说你计划乘坐探险者号从那儿出去
Also heard you're planning to take a Jumper out...
我想那正是天棚的作用
I figure that's what the door on the roof is for...
其他人带枪了吗？
Anyone else call shot gun?
只是开出去看看而已
Just gonna drive around the planet check it out...
只是出去看看
Oh you're just checking out the planet...
哦，这样啊
我是说这很酷
oh never mind then that's cool I mean...
比出去看看我又更好的事在等着我去做
I've got better things to be doing
than cruising around the planet in a space ship.
你真像个孩子
你知道吗？
You're like a kid you know that?
是的，长官
我带了些飞行中可以吃的东西
Yes sir.
I brought along something to eat on the ride...
什么？
What's that?
来个美味的……火鸡三明治怎么样？
How about a nice... turkey sandwhich...
我们走
Lets go.
不管是谁，把下一个叫进来
Send in whoever's next please...
Teyla
我没想到是你
I wasn't expecting you.
我很惊讶你的名单里没有我
I was surprised to be left of your list...
我认为你不需要询问了
I didn't feel it was necessary in your case...
相反，你应该先询问我
On the contrary you should have spoken to me first...
你是对的，我本该这么做
You're right... I should have.
我可以告诉你有关我的人民
的任何事情
I can tell you anything you need
to know about my people...
有没可能你并不像你自己
以为的那样了解你的人民？
Is it possible you don't know
them all as well as you think?
Weir博士，我和你有同感
I empathize with you Dr Weir...
作为领导者，我们时常要做出
艰难的抉择
As leaders we are often forced to make difficult
decisions in the interests of those we serve...
但是有很多Athosian并不是十分
理解
But many of my fellow Athosian
are not so... understanding...
我知道
但现在我对此无能为力
I know...
But there's nothing I can do about that now...
他们可以随意猜测我
调查他们的动机
People can suspect my motives
for these meeting all they want.
但你和我必须承认
我们之间有矛盾
But you and I need to agree that we have a problem...
我必须尽全力彻底查清楚
I have to do what ever I can to get to the bottom of it
现在这一步就是坐下来
和这里的每一个人会面
and right now that means sitting down
and talking to every single person here...
你该知道有离开亚特兰蒂斯的言论产生了
You should know there is talk of leaving Atlantis
我可不希望见到那一幕发生
I hope it doesn't come to that.
不是所有的改变都是百无一利的
Not all change is for the worst...
把探险者3号送到发射台上
Flight this is Jumper three we are go for bay launch.
探险者3号可以起飞
Jumper three you are good to go.
是的
Yes we are...
很奇怪我们没有感到超重
It's strange not pulling into Gs...
是啊，有些想念那种感觉
虽然以这种加速度我们可能已经玩完了
Yeah... kinda miss it. Although at this rate
of acceleration we'd be dead by now.
是吗？
yeah?
当然……如果不消除重力影响
我们承受的超重将是我们的眼睛被压出
Oh yeah... without inertial dampening we'd
be hit by so many Gs our eyes would pop...
脸皮会被撕下
the skin would pull away from our faces,
我们的脑浆会被压到
头骨的后部
our brains would squish up to the back of our skulls
而我们的内脏会四散飞溅
and our internal organs
would be crushed into these chairs
来个三明治？
What about that sandwhich?
我们将采用低轨道飞行
Flight we're going to take
a low orbit around the planet.
我们重新连接上时会告诉你们的
We'll advise when we're back in radio range...
照着做，探险者三号
好运
Copy that Jumper three... Good luck
你知道我们还没给那个行星命名
You know we still haven't named the planet yet...
我相信远古人一定给它起过名字了
I'm sure the ancients have a name for it...
叫亚特兰蒂卡之类的怎么样？
How about Atlantica or something like that.
我还以为我们已经同意
你不会再给东西起名字了
I thought we agreed you weren't
going to name anything anymore?
长官
Sir...
那是……
Is that...
大陆吗？
...land?
是的……没错……
Yes...it is...
真不知道有多大
Wonder how big it is?
大
Big.
很大……
Really big...
巨大……
It's huge...
到底怎么个巨大法？
Define huge...
一千五百万平方英里
15 million square miles...
放弃还是占领
give or take...
那样的话就是大约……
Well that would make it approximately the size of...
我算不清，但听起来确实挺巨大的
I have no idea but it sounds huge...
需要多久能到达那里？
How long would it take us to get there?
用探险者号25分钟
25 minutes by Jumper from ground to ground...
我在南边的表格上看见有些起伏
也许他们是在用未来的滑板冲浪
I saw some sweet breakers on the south table...
there may be surfing in our futur...
我们需要派个队伍去对那里的
泥土和水进行取样
We should send a team
to go get soil and water samples.
没错，如果那里的土地适宜耕种
那么将会极大解决我们的食物问题
He's right if the land's arable it could solve
a lot of our food productions problems
事实上我在想其他问题……
Actually I was thinking of something else...
不是冲浪？
Not surfing?
不是，长官……只要Athosian人还在城市里
我们就不能恢复外星任务
No sir... We can't resume offworld missions
as long as the Athosian remain in the city...
所以你想把他们放到那个地方是吗
So you want to dump them on the main land
少校，听起来好像是我们把他们
拉去送死
Sound like we're sending them out to die major...
那你们怎么知道……
Well how the hell would you know...
——那里看起来很荒芜
——刚才我们还在冲浪
- It looked pretty wild down there...
- A second ago we were going surfing...
那是在我们在寻找怪物以及
Well that was after we check for monsters and...
臭虫和空间有关的东西以后的事情了
bugs and other space related things...
我不觉得那里比他们原来的
居住地要差
I can't imagine it would be worse
than their original home world...
那可能只是你的一厢情愿罢了
That could be just failure
of imagination on your part.
不管怎样，调查一下就
能得到一些我们需要的信息
And any case a survey would
tell us what we need to know...
你不在认真地考虑这件事情？
You're not seriously thinking about this?
起先我们是他们离开家园的原因
We're the reason they had
to leave their planet in the first place.
少校，当时情况很复杂
This is a complicated situation major...
你什么意思？
Well what does that mean...
我并不想排除任何一种可能
在这个节骨眼上
It means I'm not about to rule
anything out... at this point...
Weir博士
你们在这里发现了一片新大陆是真的么？
Dr weir...
Is it true you have discovered land on this world
是啊
Yes it is
那么我们的人民想离开
去那里开拓
Then my people wish to take our leave to explore it.
真的吗？
You would?
我们在这里不受欢迎了
We're no longer welcome here...
不是这样的
That's not the case
这样我们至少显得有用
因为我们不能靠近星际门
And it will make us useful as long
as we have no access to the gate...
我们甚至还不知道那里是否安全
We don't even know if it's safe...
我们可以为我们的人民决定
We can determine that... for both our people...
我不明白……直到现在你
一直要求进入星际门
I don't get it... up until now you have been
insisting on access to the Stargate
现在你又要求和星际门断绝关系
and now you're proposing to deliberately
cut yourself off from it...
我们不能离开
We cannot leave...
我们也不能留下
and we cannot stay...
那片新大陆给了我们第三种选择
The main land presents us with a third option...
我明白了
I see
你曾说过这只是暂时的措施
You said yourself this was a temporary measure
是的，当然
Yes of course...
你有办法保证亚特兰蒂斯和新大陆之间的联络
You have the means to assure us
passage between Atlantis and the main land...
当你决定恢复使用星际门的时候
when you decide to resume use of the gate.
如果我们可以恢复执行通过星际门的任务
And if we resume our missions through the Stargate
并且并不是每次都碰到幽灵
and stop encountering the wraith at every turn...
那只会证明Athosian人里有叛徒
it will only prove that there is a spy on the Athosian.
而如果你们还是每次都遭到
幽灵的攻击
And when you continue to encounter
the wraith at every turn...
那将证明我们的清白
it will only prove our innocence.
你们和Teyla讨论过这件事了吗？
Have you discussed this with Teyla?
Teyla已经作了决定
Teyla has made her decision...
我知道你不会和我们一起来
I understand you are not coming with us.
Weir博士安排好了亚特兰蒂斯和新大陆
之间的通信
Dr weir has arranged for communications
between Atlantis and the main land...
如果你们需要我们的帮助
Should you ever need our assistance...
替我们谢谢她
Thank her for us...
我希望……
I hope...
——我不希望你们有人认为我……
——Teyla
- I don't want anyone to believe that I'm...
- Teyla.
时候到了
The time has come.
保重……
Go safely...
你也是
And you...
我还从未和我的人民分开过
I've never been separated
from my people before...
这一定很难受
但你知道你一定会再见到他们的
It must be hard...
but you know you'll see them again...
你们怀疑你们回不了地球了？
You doubt that you will
one day return to earth...
我可怀疑不起
I can't afford that doubt
你是说你没法让事实显露出来
You mean you can not afford to let them show.
你仍然是个领导者，Teyla
You're still a leader Teyla...
你是为了你的人民和他们的未来
这样做的
You are doing this for
you're people and for their future...
他们知道的
They know that.
少校，又要穿过星际门而激动吗？
Anxious to step through the gate again Major?
——是啊
——我们都……
- Yes I am...
- We all our...
——你有什么特别的要我们带回来吗？
——呃……没有，谢谢
- You like us to bring back anything special?
- uh... no thanx...
杂货？新服装？餐具？
Groceries? A new outfit? Flatware...
嗯……不了……
我只要你们完整的回来
Hmm... no...
just yourselves in one piece please.
接通
Dial it up.
注意安全
Be safe.
有好东西？
Well good stuff?
我都不知道怎么形容有多
奇妙了
I can't even begin to tell
you how fascinating this is.
人类学的奇妙还是真的奇妙？
Anthropologist fascinating
or actual fascinating?
也许用奇妙形容不是很恰当
Yes well maybe fascinating isn't the right word.
也许吧
还有多久？
Maybe not.
How much longer?
据观测
我们差不多该回去了
Realistically.
We'll probably be needing to come back...
这里有太多的东西……
there's just so much here...
我知道
有什么办法可以快一些吗？
Well I can see that
is there any way to speed things up?
当然，找个可以翻译废墟上的
东西的人
well sure find me someone
who can translate some of the ruin.
你是说这里有原住民？
Did you say there were natives here?
他们是很害羞的种族
They are very shy people.
我们刚一穿过星际门
他们也许找地方躲起来了
They probably went into hiding
the moment we came through the gate.
有没办法可以让他们出来
帮我们一把呢？
Is there any way you can coax them out.
Have them give us a hand?
希望不大，但我试试看
It is unlikely but I could try.
中尉，和她去一趟
Ltd, go with her.
如果我单独行动会好一些
It would be better if I went alone.
你是单独的啊
You will be alone,
和Ford少尉
with ltd Ford.
也许他们不在附近
Maybe they're not around.
他们在附近
但对他们来说你是个陌生人
They are near
but you are a stranger to them.
只要你在这儿
他们就不会出来
They will not come out of hiding
so long as you are with me.
少尉，他们不是危险的人
我没事的
They are not a dangerous people Ltd.
I will be fine.
好吧，我在这等着
Alright I'll wait here.
如果有需要就呼叫我
Call me on the radio if you need me.
有幽灵！！回到星际门
WRAITH!!! Back to the Gate Now!!!
Teyla！！少校，
怎么了？
Teyla!!
Major what's the situation?
少尉，我们真交火呢
你必须绕路靠近星际门了
Ltd we're taking fire.
You're going to have to circle around
to get back to the gate.
Teyla不和我在一起，她去……
Teyla's not with me she went to get...
找到她，把她找回来
Find her.
Get her back.
走！
Move out!
Lumano！McKay！抓住少校
Lumano! McKay! grab the Major.
——那Ford少尉呢？
——快！
- What about Ltd Ford?
- Now!!
快关上星际门，他们就在我们后面
Shut it down they're right behind us.
我们必须回去
We have to go back.
Teyla呢？Ford少尉呢？
Teyla? Ltd Ford?
仍在那个星球上
我们现在必须回去
Still on the planet.
We have to go back now!
我反对
门那头都是幽灵！
I'd advise against it.
You have wraith all over the gate.
我们不能把他们留在那儿
We can't just leave them there.
有多少？
How many?
不好说，他们有很多人都在3线以后
Its hard to say most of them were behind the tree line.
我们在这儿是浪费时间
我们需要找营救的办法
We're wasting time here
we need to mount a rescue operation.
博士，在没有搞清一切以前我是不会
派任何人通过星际门的
I'm not going to send anyone through
that gate until I have all the facts Doctor.
Teyla和Ford少尉是怎么和你们分开的？
How did Teyla and Ltd Ford get separated from you?
他们去搜索试图寻找到一些原住民
They went to check out the area and
try to make contact with some of the natives.
是谁的主意？
And whose idea was that?
我的，她是服从我的命令
Mine.
She was following my orders.
你怎么不在医疗室待着？
Shouldn't you be back at the infirmary?
不，我好了
我没有被正正得击中
No I'm fine I didn't take a full blast.
少校，你为什么不和他们一起去？
Why didn't you go with them major?
那个星球的居民很容易受惊吓
Well the natives of that planet are easily spooked.
Teyla说人多的话会把他们吓跑的
Teyla thought we'd scare
them off with a big group.
又是Teyla
Teyla did...
——军士，怎么了？
——我们中埋伏的时候她正巧不在
- What's that sergeant?
- She was conveniently absent during the ambush.
所以你是说Ford，是他干的？
So was Ford maybe it was him?
我只是陈述事实，长官
I'm just stating a fact sir.
军士，我只想说一遍
Sergeant I am only going to say this once.
少校，按照规矩你可以
随意的申诉我
With all due respect Major
You can reprimand me if you wish...
但你的队伍已经6次中埋伏了
but its been six times
your team has been compromised.
上次任务
只有一个Athosian人知道这件事情
Only one Athosian knew about this last mission.
我们受到一个意外的外星信号
We have an unscheduled off-world activation.
是Teyla
It's Teyla's IDC.
收到电波传送
Receiving a radio transmission.
我是Teyla，Ford少尉受伤了
This is Teyla.
Ltd Ford has been wounded.
幽灵和我们很靠近
The wraith are closing in on our position.
放下防御体的话，我们就门户大开
幽灵会攻进来的
You put down that shield and we could be
opening up this base to a wraith attack.
亚特兰蒂斯，让我们过去
Atlantis, please let us through.
Ford少尉，你能确认一下情况吗？
Ltd Ford can you confirm the situation.
他失去知觉了
我们快要绝望了
He is unconscious.
Our situation grows desperate.
再过一会儿我们只有冲过星际门了
别无选择
Soon we will have no choice
but to go through the Stargate.
我们放下防御体的话，谁知道
她会带些什么东西过来
We drop that shield and who knows
what she'll bring through the gate with her.
快把门打开！！
Open up the damn gate!!
放下防御体
Lower the shield.
如果她在给幽灵报信
那为什么把Ford带回来
If she were helping the Wraith
why bother bringing Ford back.
那为什么多次一举要回来？
In fact why bother coming back at all?
她在亚特兰蒂斯这儿会更有用
She's off more use to them here in Atlantis
那就是她假装救Ford少尉的原因
as for apparently rescuing Ltd Ford.
她把他拖回星际门
有什么假装的？
She carried him through the gate
what's apparent about that.
他失去知觉了，长官
我们还不知道发生什么了
He's unconscious sir
we still don't know what happened.
——够了
——提出安全的担心是我的本职！
- Oh that's enough
- Its my job to express security concerns.
——我已经受够了你的担心
——再一次的，按照规矩，少校
- I've heard enough of your concerns.
- Again with all due respect Major ...
我觉得你把你个人的感觉置于……
I believe you're putting
your personal feeling in front of your...
你可以走了
You're dismissed.
是的，长官
Yes sir.
怎么了？
What?
是我让他负责安全事务的
I'm the one who put him in charge of security.
是啊
Yes you did...
如果你想让我走，那就请
and if you want to dismiss me.
Go ahead.
你为什么不去看看Ford少尉怎么样了？
Why don't you go see how Ltd Ford is doing.
你想让我搜她的东西？
You want me to go through her stuff?
我们在找武器，话筒
录音设备
We're looking for weapons,
transmitters, recording devices...
所有超过Athosian科技水平的东西
anything that looks like its beyond
the Athosian level of technology.
如果我找不到的话
是不是还要脱光衣服检查？
And if I don't find anything
we move onto a strip search?
尽管做
Just do it.
我们在回去的路上
我们受到攻击
We were on our way back,
when we came under fire.
甚至没看清他们是谁
Didn't even see them.
他们向星际门进发的时候
我们又交火了
We returned fire they made for the gate.
我从背后被击中
她真是救了我一命，少校
I was shot from behind.
She saved my ass back there major.
当然
Of course she did.
少校，我，呃……Ford，你感觉如何？
全身发麻？
Major I oh... Ford how are you feeling
pins and needles all over?
哦，跟我一样
Oh yeah welcome to the club.
不，我躲过了击昏器的袭击
No sir I managed to dive out
of the way of the stun blast.
一定是回来的时候撞到了头
I must have hit my head on the way down.
——你撞到了头？
——少校，我要让你看些东西
- You hit your head?
- Major I need you to see something.
我没事
I'll be fine.
——这到底是什么？
——我知道看起来很怪
- What the hell is this?
- I know how it looks.
这是Bates警官拿来的
It was a special request from Sergeant Bates.
——我一定要揍那个臭小子一顿
——少校
- I'm gonna bust that Son of a Bitch.
- Major...
Teyla和这次意外无关
Teyla has nothing to do with this.
可事实是他是对的
The thing is he was right.
Bates是对的？
Bates was right?
我知道，我当时也和你一样奇怪
看这个
I know I was as surprised as you are.
Look at this.
这是她的纪念盒
是个话筒
Its her locket.
It's a transmitter,
它在传播一个连续的信号
Its been broadcasting a continuous signal
如果我不仔细研究
我一定无法发现
I wouldn't even have noticed
if I hadn't been looking for it specifically.
——我知道了
——什么？
- I found it.
- What?
在我们第一次见面的时候
Back on her planet the first time we met.
Teyla带我到遗迹上参观
它半埋在土里，我拾起来给她的
Teyla took me to the old ruins.
That was half buried in dirt I gave it to here.
这是我许多年前丢的
I lost this years ago.
这个纪念盒不足发出很强的信号
传播得很远
The locket isn't powerful enough
to send a signal very far
更不用说穿越子空间
certainly not through subspace.
现在，我猜是在某些星球上有
这个设备的接收器
Now, my guess is there are probably relay
devices on certain planets
可以接到它发出的信号
然后报告给最近的幽灵
that probably pick up the transmission
and alert the nearest hive ship.
那就是我们被攻击的原因
Those were the planets we were attacked.
小伙子还欠我们一个道歉
Boy do we owe a few people an apology.
Teyla是无意识泄露了你们的行踪
Teyla had no idea
she was giving away your position.
她说这是她父亲给她的礼物
She said it was a present from her father...
她小时候把它丢了
she lost it when she was a kid.
在Sheppard少校拾起它把它激活以前
它很可能处于休眠状态
It was probably dormant until
Major Sheppard picked it up activated it.
如果她小时候戴过
那他们那时为什么没有受到攻击
If she wore it as a kid
why weren't they attacked back then...
我不是说它是处于休眠状态吗？
Didn't I just say it was dormant??
但你也说它一碰就可以激活了
But if it was activated by touch.
你没听清
我说Sheppard少校把它激活了
You're not listening.
I said major Sheppard activated it
就幽灵了解的情况看
As far as the wraith are concerned
Teyla只是另一个人类而已
Teyla is just another human being.
他们一定没兴趣跟踪她
They would have no interest tracking her...
——而另一方面，Sheppard少校
——拥有远古基因
- now Major Sheppard on the other hand.
- Has the Ancient gene.
没错，一方面
幽灵和远古人曾经打过仗
Exactly. Now at one point
the wraiths and the ancients were at war
幽灵发明了可以探测远古人的传输设备
the wraiths created a transmission
device to detect ancients
所以Athosian人认为那是不错的小饰品
SO some Athosian thought this would
make a nice little necklace.
我怎么知道？
How could I possibly know that?
我是在说什么？
重点是……
What am I answer man?
The point is...
不是Teyla也不是其他Athosian人
该对此事负责
It wasn't Teyla or any other
Athosian for that matter.
如果真是这样的话
If that's the case
我们可以将计就计
we can use it against them.
——你看起来有些紧张
——不，我也是一员，我要参与
- You seem nervous.
- No... I'm part of this team I'm doing this.
没错
我刚才是说你有些紧张
Yes you are.
I just said you seemed nervous.
哦，真的？我还以为你暗示我
不用参加了
Oh really... I thought you said Rodney
you don't have to do this.
——你当然要参加
——该死，我要参加
- Yes you do.
- Damn right I'm doing this...
我感觉我走到另一个极端了
despite the fact the feeling has
a completely turned my extremities.
——你迟到了
——对不起
- You're late.
- Sorry
既然幽灵获得了再生的能力
Now given the wraiths regenerative abilities
要杀掉他们需要花些力气
killing one requires some amount of effort.
活捉是另一项任务
Catching one alive is going
to be a whole other deal
就这些选择
你们要和幽灵决斗
for any of these options to work
your wraith has to be on the ground.
我们去拜访的上一个星球飞船无法进入
The last planet we visited was inaccessible by ship.
星际门附近的废墟会迫使
幽灵徒步过来
and the ruins around the Stargate should
force the wraith to come through on foot.
那样的话
你们就可以使用这个
In which case,
You'll be able to use these.
这是一个击昏手榴弹
This is a stun grenade.
里面填充了钠钾混合液
Its filled with a mixture of aluminum
and potassium percolate
点燃以后产生一个高压波
that when ignited produces a high pressure wave
会使目标受到剧烈的
光和声的打击
that will overwhelm the intended
target with intense light and sound.
如果那样还不能使他的头嗡嗡响
If that doesn't get his head ringing.
那么还有这个
In addition, you've got your tazer
射程15-20英尺
with a range of 15 to 20 feet
它会产生一个高压
it delivers a high voltage low Ambridge charge
限制身体的电子信号暂时的麻痹上当者
that limits the body's electrical
signals temporarily paralyzing the victim.
少校，我是Ford
Major this is Ford.
你找到什么了，少尉？
What you Got Ltd?
我们找到伙伴了
We've got company.
4个
Four of them.
很好，按原计划行动
Alright then we go as planned.
是的，长官
Yes, Sir.
你看起来还是很紧张
You still seem nervous.
不不不不，很好
没事的，很好
No no no, its good good.
All go, all good.
Teyla
Teyla.
这是我们要活捉的，放Tazer！
This one's ours boys. Tazers!
自毁系统，快闪开！
Self destruct. Take cover!!
少校！
McKay博士？
Major!
Dr McKay?
你还好吧
You ok?
我没事，这……这很好玩
I'm fine. This is... this is fun for me.
放松……不要自毁了
Easy... Don't go blowing yourself up.
Teyla，对不起
P Teyla
Excuse me.
我原来希望能在你去
新大陆以前找到你
I was hoping to catch you before
you headed back to the main land.
我听说他们干的不错
I hear they're doing well.
很好
Very well.
据Halling说，他们正忙着
种下个季度的植物呢
According the Halling they're busily
planting crops for the next harvest.
听到这我很高兴
I'm glad to hear it.
我会告诉他们发生什么了
I will tell them what has happened,
很快我们就都会忘了
这几星期发生的事情
hopefully in time we will all be able
to put the events of the past week behind us.
是的，我感觉到最近几天
Yes, I am aware that the last few days
你的压力很大
have been particularly difficult for you.
Weir博士，我相信
I believe, Dr Weir.
如果在你的位置上
我也会这么做的
That in your place,
I would have done the same.
谢谢
Thank you.
再说一次
你们真是顽固的种族
Again,
Your kind is persistent.
我还以为你们该放弃了
I would have thought you'd given up by now.
哦，我可有的是时间
Aww hell I've got all the time in the world.
你却在一个陌生的地方
Now you on the other hand.
远古人对防御层可是十分在行的
The ancients were pretty good at shields
不是吗？
and stuff like that, weren't they?
我给你一个星期，最多两个
I give you a week, maybe two tops.
浪费时间
You waste your time.
我不会告诉你们的
I'll provide you with no information.
我在想什么更痛苦一点
被枪击还是饥饿呢？
Wonder what hurts more
the gun shot wound or the hunger?
因为我很乐意帮忙
但我不知道McKay把食谱放在哪儿了
Because I'd love to help out
but how did McKay put it?
估计我们没法满足您的要求
We can't meet your dietary requirements.
一旦我自由了，你就是我的第一样食物
When I am free, you will be the first that I feed upon.
好啊来啊
Okie dokie.
我把自己做成一个三明治好了
I'm going to go make myself a sandwhich.
人类
Human.
你认为抓到我就是胜利
You think you've won a victory by my capture
但把我带到这儿只会加速你们的毁灭
but by bringing me here
you've only hastened your own doom.
只是时间问题
Its only a matter of time
他们迟早会来救我的
before the others of my kind come to rescue me.
等他们到了
And when they do,
这个世界就没有你们的藏身之地了
They'll be no where in this world you can hide.
那现在就保持乐观吧
Stay positive now.